Hello friends welcome back to new video
and in today's video we will talk
about Aaa Lord General Insurance Company,
this company has recently announced
dividend, what is the dividend amount,
when is the record date and
we have also done fundamental analysis of this company in this video,
so definitely watch the video completely, if you are
new to the channel then definitely subscribe,
you can see that the current price is
14612 p8, that is, there has been a
great gain of 4.99 today,
looking at the graph of last five days, there has been a
gain of 1.02 pence in the last five days, looking at the
graph of last one month, there has been a decline of 4.13 pence in the last one month,
looking at the graph of last six months, there has been a gain of 99.94 pence in the last 6 months,
let's see the max graph, the
company was listed in the stock market
on 29 September
2017, at that time the price of the stock was
80.2 pence, from then till now the price of the stock is
13  It has
increased from ₹6.97 to ₹
161.5 now. So let's find out what the company does.
ICI Lord General Insurance is
one of the leading and established private
sector general insurance companies in India.
It offers a well-diversified range of
products and risk management solutions
through multiple distribution channels. The
market cap of the stock is ₹
7923 crores. The stock's PA is 41.3. The
book value is ₹48. The dividend yield is ₹39. The ROI is
22.5. The ROI is
16.9. And the face value is ₹10. You
can also study the charts here to see the pros and
cons. The company is almost debt-
free. The company has been maintaining a healthy
dividend payout of
29.6%. The promoter holding has increased by
3.36% over the last
quarter. Here you can also see the peer comparison. The
company comes at number five
position as per the market cap in the
insurance and finance and investment
sector.  You can also study the quarterly results here. Let's
see the profit and loss
as of March 2024. Sales are
2487 crores and net profit is
1919 crores. You can also study the balance sheet here. So,
they have fixed assets
of 701 crores. Cash flow ratio is also mentioned here.
Let's see the
shareholding pattern as of March 2024.
Promoters have 51.27 shares. F has
23.05 shares. D has 15.96 shares.
Government has % shares and public has
9.59 shares. Number of shareholders is
239,489. So the big news is that the company has
announced dividend, so the dividend
amount is ₹6 per share. So, if you have
ICICI Lord shares, then you are going to get a
dividend of ₹100 per share and
its record date is 7th June.  2024
So if you have shares of AAAAA Lord Insurance
Company as on 7th June 2024 then
you are going to get a dividend of ₹ per share.
So this was the big news from this company. For such
interesting dividend news, stock
splits and bonus shares,
do subscribe to the channel and turn
on the bell notifications so that you
get instant video updates. Thanks for watching. Have
a great day ahead.